Guide to the Robert N. Hampton lecture notes, 1946-1952.
Hampton, Robert N. lecture notes, 1946-1952
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert N. Hampton lecture notes, 1946-1952.
21-10-3203
Robert Nelson, 1920- Hampton
.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, typescripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Graduate student lecture notes, reports, and other papers from Agricultural Economics 187, Farm Appraisal, fall 1946; Land Economics 181, spring 1947; Agronomy 101, spring 1947; Economics 202, Money, Currency, and Banking, fall 1947; Agricultural Economics 151, Prices, summer 1950; and Agricultural Economics 240, Introduction to Marketing Research, fall 1952.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University M.S. Agriculture, 1947, Ph.D., 1954. Robert Hampton graduated from V.P.I. in 1941, and worked as a soil conservationist before serving as a naval officer during World War II. He returned to do gradutate work at Cornell, focusing on Farm Management and Agronomy. He received a Ph.D. in Marketing, with minors in Business Management, International Trade, and Cultural Anthropology. He served on the staff of the Dept. of Agricultural Economics in Extension and Teaching from 1953-1955. From 1955-1959, he worked in Market Promotion & Development for Dow Chemical Company; from 1959-63 as Manager of the Marketing Research Dept. of International Paper Co.; from 1964-1982 as Vice President for Marketing & International Trade for the National Council of Farmer Cooperatives; and from 1982 until his retirement in 1997 as an international trade consultant.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Graduate student lecture notes, reports, and other papers from Agricultural Economics 187, Farm Appraisal, fall 1946; Land Economics 181, spring 1947; Agronomy 101, spring 1947; Economics 202, Money, Currency, and Banking, fall 1947; Agricultural Economics 151, Prices, summer 1950; and Agricultural Economics 240, Introduction to Marketing Research, fall 1952.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hampton, Robert Nelson, 1920-; Cornell University--Graduate students.; New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Agricultural Economics.; New York State College of Agriculture.Dept. of Agronomy.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Economic aspects.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Lecture Notes, 1940's-1950's (Box 1)
  - Land Economics, 1940's (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agronomy, 1940's (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Economics-Farm Appraisal, 1940's (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Exam and Lecture Notes, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Exams and Notes, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Economics-Money, Currency, and Banking, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agricultural Economics-Graduate Students, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Lab Exercises, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Lab Exercises, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Lab Exercises, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Economics (Geography)-Lab Exercises, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Economics (151), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Economics-Exams and Notes, 1950's (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Economics-Introduction to Marketing Research (240), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II. Articles and Conferences, 1960-1987 (Box 1)
  - "The Market for Turfiber"-by Hampton, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Publicity-Food Marketing, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Publicity-Farm Cooperatives, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Toward the Integration of World Agriculture", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Leaders' Trade Conference, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural Leaders' Trade Conference, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Publicity-Farm Cooperatives, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Innovative Marketing for Cooperatives-Seminar, n. 1, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Innovative Marketing for Cooperatives-Seminar, n. 2, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Agexport, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - International Trade Competitiveness Seminar, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Coalition for Trade Expansion with Canada, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)